Finding Aid for the Lucile, Lady Duff-Gordon Drawings LSC.0624
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 204, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [two piece dress suit with blue polka dotted collar, purple trimmed cuffs, and black pockets with squiggly designs, same squiggly designed black bands on cuffs]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 212; Foxing on bottom left-hand corner, grease spots on upper and middle area, prick marks on lower right-hand corner. (Box 22)
- 205, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [dark yellow trench coat with black striped collar, black buttoned belt and folded cuffs]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 213; Foxing on bottom right-hand corner and upper left-hand corner, smudging on lower left-hand corner, and upper and lower right-hand areas. (Box 22)
- 208, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [Asian-styled pink and purple robe-like top with matching dress pants, multi-colored tassels on robe-top, with orange, gold and red designs on front]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 214; Foxing everywhere, smudging on upper and lower left-hand corners, bottom right-hand corner, and lower middle area, watercolor mark on middle right-hand area, slightly peeled top edge, bent upper left-hand corner. (Box 22)
- 207, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, Lucy Duff Gordon stamp signature, [dark yellow overcoat with green collar and banded sleeves, and floral printed belt]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 215; Foxing on bottom left-hand corner, smudging on middle left-hand area. (Box 22)
- 208, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [pale blue robe-like jacket with ruffles and thin orange trimmings, high collar and ribbon at the neck]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 216; Foxing on bottom left and right-hand corners, middle right-hand edge and upper right-hand corner, slightly bent upper left- hand corner, indent on top right-hand edge. (Box 22)
- 209, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [two piece gray dress suit with banded sleeves, and pink, black, and lavender colored designs on front]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 217; Foxing on top left-hand edge, smudging on upper right-hand edge and middle bottom area. (Box 22)
- 210, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [two piece blue-gray dress suit with flower printed collar, four buttons on front, with green hat]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 218; Foxing on upper right-hand area, and bottom left-hand corner, smudging along lower right-hand edge, and bottom left and right-hand corners. (Box 22)
- 2/3, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [sleeveless pink layered dress with silver printed designs on hem, flower design on bodice]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 219; Foxing on upper right-hand corner, lower right-hand area, and bottom left and right-hand corners, smudging on bottom right- hand corner, pink watercolor mark on lower right-hand area, bent upper left-hand corner, slightly striated top edge. (Box 22)
- 2/5, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [pale yellow and white blouse with lacy floral designs and pale yellow semi-pleated long skirt with pockets, blue buttons on blouse, yellow buckled belt]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 220; Foxing along top edge, and middle left-hand area, discolored area on upper left-hand edge, striated top edge with glue-like residue. (Box 22)
- 2/7, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [long trailing dark green dress with green banded sheer sleeves, floral designs near cuffs,, blue wide-brimmed hat with purple ribbon]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 221; Foxing on upper right-hand area, and bottom right-hand corner, smudging on bottom and top left-hand corners, discoloration along upper right-hand edge, glue-like residue along top edge. (Box 23)
- 2/8, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [black dress with white lacy designed collar and cuffs, three-fourth length sleeves, and long black sash with tassels]., 1916-17; UCLA Drawing No. 222; Foxing on upper left-hand edge, bottom left-hand area, and bottom right-hand corner, smudging on bottom right-hand corner, peeled spot on middle left-hand area, and peeled top edge. (Box 23)
- 211, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner [V-necked silver dress with sheer silver banded sleeves, ruffles on skirt, and long silver floral printed black sash]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 223; Foxing on top left-hand corner, and lower left-hand edge, "31" written faintly on upper right-hand area, glue-like residue along top edge. (Box 23)
- 212, pen and pencil sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [orange-red and silver sleeveless dress with pink flower designs on bodice, and silver trimmed hems]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 224; Foxing on top area, upper left-hand edge, bottom right-hand corner and bottom edge, smudging on middle area, slightly peeled spot on middle left-hand area, bent upper left-hand corner. (Box 23)
- 213, pen and pencil sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [white ruffled dress with pink rectangular bands on skirt, circular floral prints on bodice and skirt, with pale blue, purple, and pink sash]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 225; Foxing on top left-hand edge, upper right-hand edge, bottom edge, and lower left-hand edge, smudging on top left-hand corner, upper middle right-hand edge, and middle left-hand area, glue-like residue on top edge. (Box 23)
- 214, pen and pencil sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [dress with sheer sleeved top and long yellow skirt, white floral designs on bodice, and long blue sash]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 226; Foxing on top left-hand edge, middle and lower left-hand edge, bottom edge, and upper right-hand edge, smudging on lower left-hand corner and middle left-hand area, glue-like residue along top edge. (Box 23)
- 215, pen and pencil sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [pale green and yellow dress with sheer shawl-like top wrap, silver design prints and gold tassel on shawl, green, yellow, and silver sash]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 227; Foxing along top edge, upper right and left-hand areas, and middle left-hand edge, smudging on bottom left-hand corner, and middle left and right-hand edges, slightly bent upper left-hand corner. (Box 23)
- 216, pen sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [sleeveless white dress with two long black sashes, pale pink ruffled dress underneath]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 228; Foxing on top right-hand edge, upper left-hand corner, upper left-hand edge, and bottom left-hand corner, smudging on top right-hand edge, white-out grime on upper and lower middle areas, on sketch, glue-like residue on top edge. (Box 23)
- 217, pen and pencil sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [purple-pink colored dress with long shawl-like sheer top, purple sash with red and green flower prints tied in a big ribbon]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 229; Foxing on upper left-hand edge, and along right-hand edge, smudging on upper and lower left-hand corners, glue-like residue on top edge. (Box 23)
- 218, pen and pencil sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [blue-gray dress with purple bands running vertical along outer layer, sheer pale blue jacket with gold printed designs and green trimmings, blue sash with red and green tassels]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 230; Foxing on upper right-hand edge and along bottom edge, smudging on bottom middle edge, middle left-hand edge, upper right-hand area, and upper middle area, bent upper left-hand corner, glue-like residue on top edge. (Box 23)
- 2/2, pen sketch of back view on lower left-hand corner, [long yellow dress with sheer yellow shawl-like top, long green floral design on bodice, yellow and silver-design printed sash]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 231; Foxing all along right edge, bottom edge, and upper left-hand area, smudging along all four edges, bent lower right-hand corner. (Box 24)
- 2/4, pen and pencil sketch of back view on lower right-hand corner, [long sleeved pink dress with silver speckled designs, green trimming on hem of dress, purple multi-colored speckled sash with intricate tasseled ornament hanging from side]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 232; Foxing on upper and middle left-hand edge, smudging on lower left-hand corner, and middle right-hand edge, glue-like residue along top edge. (Box 24)
- 219, pencil sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [green dress with gold flowered trimming along ruffles cascading down across the skirt and sheer gold top with purple fringed trimmings along sleeves]., 1917/Fin; UCLA Drawing No. 233; Foxing along bottom and top, glue residue on top edge, smudge on top right area. (Box 24)
- 220, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [yellow and silver dress with sheer top and three bands of fur on sleeves]., 1917/Fin; UCLA Drawing No. 234; Foxing on upper left and right-hand areas and middle right-side, glue residue on top, grime on bottom of sketch. (Box 24)
- 221, pencil sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [pink and grayish dress with white ruffled collar and white ruffled placket with ribbons running down middle of dress, with fur trimmings on cuffs and skirt, with matching veiled hat and purse]., 1917/Fin; UCLA Drawing No. 235; Foxing on bottom edge, right-hand side, and upper left-hand area, bent upper left-hand corner. (Box 24)
- 222, pencil sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [yellow dress with fur hems and fur-trimmed collar and sheer sleeves]., 1917/Fin; UCLA Drawing No. 236; Foxing on bottom left-hand edge, lower and middle right-hand side, top middle edge, and middle left-hand side, bent top edge and bottom right-hand corner, peeled top edge. (Box 24)
- 224, colored sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [silver dress with gold ruffled and stripped bottom with gold prints along ruffles, gold and black bowed sashes]., 1917/Fin; UCLA Drawing No. 237; Smudged lower and middle left-hand area, erased sketch on bottom right-hand corner, colored spot on upper right-hand area, bent upper right-hand edge. (Box 24)
- 225, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [sheer blue stripped dress flared thigh length ruffles, with yellow, pink, orange, and green sash and long ribbons]., 1917/Fin; UCLA Drawing No. 238; Foxing on bottom right-hand corner, lower right-hand area, bent lower left-hand side, small black mark on middle left-hand edge, grime on upper area of sketch. (Box 24)
- 226, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [white dress with ruffles and blue ribbons along lower part of dress and flowered designs on hem, and pink shawl with flowered designs and fur trimmings]., 1917/Fin; UCLA Drawing No. 239; Foxing on bottom right and left-hand corners, upper left-hand side, smudge on bottom and middle left-hand area, bent upper right-hand corner. (Box 24)
- 227, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [silver spotted sheer pink dress with ruffled collar and sleeves and layered ribbons running down all around lower part of dress]., 1917/Fin; UCLA Drawing No. 240; Foxing on middle right-hand edge, upper and bottom right-hand corners, and middle left-hand side, bent upper right-hand edge and top left-hand corner, glue reside on top, smudge on lower middle area. (Box 24)
- 273, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [blue jacket with yellow and purple collar and purple and blue cuffs over light pink dress]., 1917; UCLA Drawing No. 241; Foxing on all four sides, glue residue on top, bent upper and bottom left-hand corner, and bottom right-hand corner. (Box 25)
- 278, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [dark brown dress with fur collars and cuffs and on lower part of dress with dark purple hat with blue and black plume]., 1917/Fin; UCLA Drawing No. 242; Foxing on middle and lower left-hand edge and top edge, smudge on upper and lower right-hand area, slightly bent lower right-hand edge. (Box 25)
- 2/10, pen sketch of back view on bottom right-hand corner, [harem style green dress with gold designs and purple veil]., 1917/Fall; UCLA Drawing No. 243; Smudging on middle right-hand area, creased top area, peeled top edge. (Box 25)
- 2/9, pen sketch of back view on bottom left-hand corner, [purple coat with tiger print collar, cuffs, and hems with grey dress underneath]., 1917/Fin; UCLA Drawing No. 244; Foxing along top edge, lower left-hand area, and bottom middle edge, spot on lower middle area, smudge on upper right- hand area, bent upper left-hand corner. (Box 25)
- 2/12, [white wedding gown with flower designs and tiara with mid-length veil]., 1923; UCLA Drawing No. 245; Foxing on bottom left-hand area, middle right-hand side, and upper left-hand corner. (Box 25)
- 2/13, [grayish dress with flowers on sides of dress and bottom of the left-hand side of tasseled bodice and collar, with matching head band]., 1923; UCLA Drawing No. 246; Foxing on all 4 sides. (Box 25)
- 2/11, [ yellow dress with elliptical white spotted designs and lace collar with green and white head band]., [no date]; UCLA Drawing No. 247; Foxing along left side, top, upper and middle right-hand side, and bottom right-hand edge. (Box 25)
- "1917 Follies," pencil sketch in lower left corner, [black tunic with sheer top, embroidered long sleeves, medallion trim, bright pink cummerbund and trim. Black trousers. Bright pink hat with long green feather]., UCLA Drawing No. 248; Fold mark in lower left corner, foxing along right edge, broken lower right corner, abrasion in lower right of sketch.. (Box 25)
- "1917 Follies," pencil sketch back view of cape in lower right corner,. [draped cape/coat with peach shawl collar, pink and blue flowers, silver accents, long ties with green tassels over long white dress with pink trim]., UCLA Drawing No. 249; Slight foxing along upper edge. (Box 25)
- "1917 Follies," [Pink sheer tunic and pants with tassel trim, embroidered panel in front]., UCLA Drawing No. 250; Discoloration and foxing along left, top and right edges. (Box 25)
- "1917 Follies," [sheer grey overdress with flared sleeves over multi-colored slip dress]., UCLA Drawing No. 251; Foxing on all edges, abrasions along upper edge, notations in upper left corner which have been partially erased. (Box 25)
- "1917 Follies," [sheer light aqua one-shouldered dress with tiered skirt with silver embroidery (?) and cummerbund at waist]., UCLA Drawing No. 252; Abrasions along upper edge. (Box 25)
- Ink sketch, front view, in lower right corner, [off the shoulder black dress with blue/grey "hoop" skirt overlay, pink trim around neckline and flared sleeves, blue cummerbund]., 1916 Automne; UCLA Drawing No. 253; Foxing along upper and right edges, red ink notations under sketch (illegible). (Box 25)
- "1917 Follies," pencil sketch, front view, in lower left corner, [sheer square-necked white dress with open flared sleeves, blue overlay, orange and fuschia trim under bustline with white medallion accent]., UCLA Drawing No. 254; Foxing along lower edge, stain in upper right corner, broken lower right corner. (Box 25)
- "1917 Follies," "Arabian nights" penciled in lower right corner, [pinkish/gold harem pants and coat with green collar and multi-colored sash with green trim.], UCLA Drawing No. 255; Slight foxing upper and lower edges, abrasions along upper edge. (Box 25)